According to rumors on the Net,
（ヤサコ）ネットのウワサによると
a few years ago, an Encoder tried to devastate the Space.
数年前に ある暗号屋が
空間を破壊しようとしたそうです
でも その暗号屋がどうなったのか
誰も知りません
But nobody knows what happened to this Encoder.
（マイコ）
もう１人の新しいお友達は…
Our second new friend is...
天沢(あまさわ)さん 天沢勇子(ゆうこ)さん
Amasawa.
Yuko Amasawa.
あら 偶然
２人とも同じユウコなのね
Oh, what a coincidence.
You two have the same name. Yuko.
（イサコ）天沢勇子です よろしく
I'm Yuko Amasawa.
Pleased to meet you.
（フミエ）
金沢(かなざわ)ってことは―
Kanazawa...?
So her parents probably work for a glasses company.
Daikoku City
The Hacker's Club
あいつの親も
メガネ会社の人かしらね
I don't know...
（ヤサコ）さあ？
でも 金沢には―
But there wasn't any Encoder in Kanazawa.
暗号屋なんて
いなかったわよ
（フミエ）暗号屋には
いろんな都市伝説があって
There are a lot of urban legends about Encoders,
正体や目的が
よく分からないのよ
but their true nature and objectives are unknown.
I thought their objective was to collect metabugs.
メタバグを集めるのが
目的じゃない？
（フミエ）それがウワサでは
Rumors say that what they take from the Space isn't just metabugs.
空間から取り出すのは
メタバグだけじゃないの
（ヤサコ）何を取り出すの？
So what else do they take?
Hmm, let's see...
さあ… そうねえ
例えばミチコさんよ
For example, Miss Michiko.
ミ… ミチコさん？
Miss Michiko?
そうよ
Yeah.
でね ミチコさんを
呼び出して契約すると
I heard that if you call out Miss Michiko and make a contract with her,
なんでも願い事を
かなえてくれるんだってさ
she'll make whatever you wish for come true!
Like having better grades in school,
テストの成績が上がるとか
家が急にお金持ちになるとか
or making your family become rich, overnight!
ちょっと探りを入れてみようか
Let's start our investigation.
こんにちは
昨日はいろいろあったわね
Hello.
So many things happened yesterday.
私はフミエ よろしくね
My name is Fumie.
Nice to meet you.
よろしく
Nice to meet you too.
こっちは優子(ゆうこ)よ
And this here is Yuko.
あら あなたも
ユウコっていうのね
So your name is Yuko too, right?
偶然ね
What a coincidence!
小此木(おこのぎ)さんのニックネームは
優しいと書いてヤサコ
Okonogi's nickname is Yasako, since her name is written with the kanji for "yasashii".
あなたは
勇ましいって書くのよね
And yours is written with the kanji for "isamashii", right?
Isamashii means brave and courageous
So your nickname should be Isako!
としたら イサコだわ
よっ イサコ！
Cool, Isako!
Your names make a pun! Cool!
ちょうど語呂も合ってて
いいじゃない
Yasako and Isako!
ヤサコ イサコって
Stop it, we're not a comedy duo!
（ヤサコ）や… やめてよ
漫才師じゃあるまいし
Amasawa,
天沢さん
これから仲良くしましょう
let's be good friends.
So please, don't do things like yesterday anymore.
でも 昨日みたいなことは
もうしないでね
Yesterday?
昨日？
あなたたちに会うのは
今回が初めてよ
Today's the first time I met either of you.
Now would you please stop talking to me?
悪いけど
あんまり話しかけないでくれる？
ふーん
I don't know who Your Majesty is,
あんたが
何様なのか知らないけれど
but don't you ever lay your hands on other people's pets again!
二度と人様のペットに
手を出すんじゃないわよ
Got it?
分かった？
What if I say I don't?
分からないと言ったら？
Then I'll make you understand; even if I need to use all my power.
実力で分からせるまでよ
Hey, Busue!
"Busue" is a word game composed
of the words Busu (ugly) and Fumie.
（ダイチ）おい ブスエ！
Are you recruiting again?
お前 また勧誘してんのか？
探偵ごっこクラブに
For your "let's play the detective" club?
You're such a pest.
うっさいわね
Nobody is gonna join your loser club!
お前のヘボクラブになんか
誰も入んねえよ
Anyway, how about joining my club?
それより俺のクラブに入れよ
It's a real cool club!
すんげえクールなクラブなんだぜ
フン
ああ… なんだ　シカトか？
Hey, are you ignoring me?
How dare you ignore the Great Daichi!
この俺様をシカトするのか？
No way she would ever join a loser boys-only club like yours!
そんな男ばかりのダメクラブ
ダメに決まってるじゃない
Shrimpy!
チビスケ
What?! Who ya callin' a shrimp?!
んだと チビスケ！
ミチコさん呼ぶぞ！
I'm gonna call out Michiko!
私だって ミチコさん呼ぶわよ
I'm gonna call out Michiko too!
Shut up!
（イサコ）うるさい！
Both of you runts are never to speak to me again.
どっちのチビスケも
もう話しかけるな
Hey boss.
（ナメッチ）オヤビン
やっぱりやっちゃるですか 転校生
It looks like that transfer student really wants a lesson.
Of course she does.
当たり前だ
But boss,
でも オヤビン
うぶな転校生をだまくらかして
weren't you the one bent on tricking her
and having her join as the first female member in the club?
我がクラブ初の女子構成員に
仕立てるぞって
意気込んでたじゃないっすか
She dared to ignore me.
俺を無視しやがった
あんなヤツはクラブに入れてやらん
I'll never let her join my club.
Then what about that other transfer student?
じゃあ あっちの転校生は
どうなんすか？
She's already Busue's friend.
（ダイチ）
あいつは すでにブスエの仲間だ
So she's our enemy.
我々の敵だ
We have to teach both of them a good lesson from the start!
最初にガツーンと
やっとかなくてはならん
Wh-What's going on?!
な… 何これ？
あっ 消えない
It won't go away!
This prank...
このイタズラは…
（２人）ニィ～
Say, "Share root access".
ヤサコ “管理共有”って言って
Sh-Share root access!
か… 管理共有
フーン
ふーん…
Okay then.
じゃあ この問題
天沢さん やってもらえる？
Amasawa, could you solve this problem?
んっ？　ニィ～
Now let's see what she's capable of.
お手並み拝見といきましょうか
消えてく？　くっ…
It's disappearing?
It looks like they both have the same speed.
スピードは互角のようね
But she's writing the answer at the same time.
でも答えを書きながらよ
Huh?
あら？　どこで操作してるのかしら
Where is she operating from?
How can she operate...?
どうやって操作してるんだ？
Who knows?
（ナメッチ）さあ？
（ダイチ）クソ！
Crap!
んっ？　それは なんすか？
What's that?
Critical Error
はい 天沢さん よくできました
Good job, Amasawa.
３倍返しっすね オヤビン
I'll pay her back double for that!
（ダイチ）許せん！
俺のメガネをこんなにしやがって…
I'll never forgive her
Downloading the Auto-Restore
for doing this to my glasses!
それにしても あいつ
全然 手を動かさなかったっすね
What's amazing
is that she didn't even move her hand.
そうなんだよ
Exactly!
手作業でしか閉じられない
タチの悪いバナーを厳選したのに
I chose especially nasty banners that could only be closed with hand movements, but...
（ガチャギリ）
もしかしたら イマーゴって
隠し機能かもしれねえぞ
It could be the so-called "Imago" secret function.
イマーゴ？
Imago?
（ガチャギリ）メガネには
公開されてない機能があってな
You know glasses have hidden functions that are unknown to the public, right?
Yes.
それがイマーゴだ
That's what Imago is.
ええ 分かったわ
（ナメッチ）へえー
Yes.
Understood.
（ダイチ）
そんなの聞いたことねえぞ
Never heard of it.
（ガチャギリ）
ああ なんだか不具合が出てな
使用禁止になったらしい
Some kind of bug came out with them.
So its use has been forbidden.
それをメーカーが
ひた隠しにしてるってウワサだ
Rumors suggest that the manufacturer is hiding it like hell.
（ダイチ）で 一体 どんな機能だ？
So what function is that?
Well,
それがね 頭で考えただけで
メガネを操作できる機能らしいのよ
they say that it allows you to control your glasses with your mind.
へえー そんなことできるんだ
I didn't know that was possible.
あの子 その機能に
アクセスできる方法を
I guess that girl somehow discovered how to access that function—
どこかで手に入れたのかも
（２人）ニィ～
でも原始的なイタズラには
対抗できないわね
But there's nothing she can do about real-life pranks.
あ～あ
しっかり受け取れよ 転校生
Be careful when you take stuff, transfer student.
あら どうしたの？
What happened?
こいつが こぼしたんです
She made it all fall out.
（マイコ）そうなの？　天沢さん
Is that true, Amasawa?
（アイコ）ホント
せちがらいヤツよね ダイチって
Daichi sure is a pest.
どっちもいい気味よ
Serves them right.
（ヤサコ）あのダイチ君って
どういう子なの？
Just what kind of person is Daichi?
単なるイタズラ坊主よ
メガネさえなけりゃね
He's just a little rascal...
...without his glasses.
でも 最近
こんなこと始めたのよ
But lately,
he's started doing things like this.
くろきゃく？
Black Customers?
“ヘイクー”って読むらしいわ
It's read "Hackers".
中国語で
“ハッカー”って意味なんだって
I heard this way of writing comes from Chinese.
使う道具は どっかの
通販駄菓子屋で買ってるらしいわ
Some say that they use special items bought at online dagashi stores.
（ダイチ）ヘコんでる ヘコんでる
She sure gave up easily!
これで おとなしくなりますかね？
With this, she's gonna be real quiet.
いや 放課後もやるぞ
No, we're gonna do it again after school.
例えば ミチコさんよ
For example, Miss Michiko.
ミチコさんか…
Miss Michiko?
あの… イサコちゃん
Um,
Isako...
天沢さん
Amasawa...
用があるなら手短に言って
If you've got something to say, make it fast.
あっ あの…
なんか昨日は驚いたけど
Well,
although I was a bit scared yesterday,
私 あなたと
仲良くしたいと思ってるの
I really want to be your friend.
同時に引っ越してくるなんて
偶然とは思えないし
I can't believe it's just a coincidence that we both moved here at the same time.
お友達になりましょ
So let's be friends.
私は あんたたちみたいに
I don't like people
気安く群れる生き物が
好きじゃないの
who blindly flock to others like you do.
From Maiko-sensei to Miss Amazawa - I have something to tell you, come here immediately.
（ヤサコ）私だって…
I don't...
私だって
気安く群れてなんかいないわ
I don't blindly flock to others.
誰だって嫌われるのは怖いわ
Everyone's afraid to be left alone.
でも それで他の人に
キツく当たっても
But being unpleasant with people
友達はできないわ
won't help you make any friends.
Me?
私が？
キツく当たりたがってるのは
あの男子でしょ
The one being unpleasant
is that boy, isn't it?
でも…
But...
当ててあげようか
Let me guess.
あなた 前の学校で
I'm guessing
you caused some trouble in your last school.
何かトラブルを
起こしたんじゃない？
いじめ？
A bully?
Wh—
何言ってるの？
What are you talking about?
（イサコ）図星のようね
So I was right.
いじめてたか
いじめられてたか
Were you the bully or the bullied?
それがバレないように
演技してたんでしょ？
You were acting so that no one would ever figure it out, right?
この街では心機一転
うまいことデビューしようって？
And you were thinking that you would start a new life here.
他はだませても
私の目はごまかせないわ
You may fool others,
but you can't fool me.
大丈夫　あなたの秘密は
誰にも言わないわ
Don't worry.
I won't tell anyone about your secret.
（フミエ）あっ ヤサコ
Yasako.
ある情報を手に入れたわ
I happened to hear a certain bit of information.
面白いことになりそうよ
Something tells me things are gonna get interesting.
（ヤサコ）面白いこと？
Interesting?
戦争よ
A war!
（ガチャギリ）
パケット料金は いくらになった？
How much did you pay for that?
（ナメッチ）あちゃ～
お年玉換算で２年分っすね
Ouch!
It was the equivalent of two years' otoshidama.
おのれ～！
Dammit!
今度はメガネで
３倍返しにしてやるのだ！
This time, with these glasses, I'll make her pay two—no, three times!
（ダイチ）おい ４年！
（アキラ）あっ はい
Hey, fourth year!
Yessir!
メッセージは送ったか？
（アキラ）あっ はい
Did you send the message?
Y-Yes!
ちゃんとサーバーも
職員室に偽装して―
I just sent it by using the server in the school's office as a proxy.
さっき送りました
先生 どこですか…
Teacher, where are—?
ハァ…
ミサイルは安物のようね
A cheap missile weapon, huh?
さっきのガキどもか
Is it those pests from before?
この！　この！
Dammit! Dammit!
（アキラ）直進くんです
Here's a Mister Forthright!
Hey, fourth year,
（ダイチ）
おい ４年 どんどん補給しろ
go recharge some more!
あっ はい
Yes, sir!
“はい”じゃねえ　“へい”だ
Don't say, "Yes, sir!"
Say, "Yeah!"
へ… へい
Yeah!
クソ！　直進くんじゃ破れねえ
Damn!
The Mister Forthright won't be able beat her!
安物っすからねえ
It's a cheap weapon after all...
追跡くんを出せ
Take out the Mister Chase!
へい
Yeah!
当たったか？
Did it get her?
（ガチャギリ）分からねえ
Dunno.
１発 いくらだ？
How much is a shot?
（ナメッチ）１発 200メタっす
200 meta per shot.
値切ってか？
And with the discount?
（ナメッチ）値切ってっす
Discount included.
あ～ せちがらいぜ
Ah, what a cruel world...!
（アキラ）
追跡くん １袋 使い切りました
I used up one bag of Mister Chase.
最後の袋も出しますか？
Should I take out the last bag?
いや それは待て
No, wait.
おい まだか？
鉄壁のハッキング方法
Haven't you found a way to hack that steel wall yet?
近い方法は載ってるんだが…
I found a way for hacking it, but...
これ… これを応用すれば
いいんじゃないですか？
You just have to apply this.
んっ？　あっ そうか！
Oh, yeah!
いねえな
She's not here.
連絡通路から こっちは
俺たちのテリトリーなんだ
From the access route on, it's our territory.
逃がさんぞ
I won't let her get away.
（イサコ）いつもこれだ
It's always like this.
何もしてなくても
あっちから手を出してくる
Even if I do nothing,
others will still attack me.
（フミエ）こりゃあ面白いわ
This is really getting interesting.
気づかれるなよ
Don't get caught.
な… なんだ こりゃ？
Wh-What's this?
A malignant access has been denied.
（ガチャギリ）防壁が阻止したぞ
Her defensive wall has intercepted the attack!
（アキラ）今のは 最近
あちこちの道路に書いてあるやつだ
That's the same sign I've seen 'round here lately!
（ダイチ）
防壁を通らなきゃ問題ねえや
It doesn't matter as long as the wall isn't breached!
それで隠れたつもりかよ
So she thinks she's out of our sight, huh?
やれ！
Attack!
直進くんを撃ち込め！
Fire the Mister Forthright!
相手してやるわ
Fine, I'll play with you.
先に仕掛けた あんたが悪いのよ
You're the one who started it, so you've got it coming.
（フミエ）
おっ やるな！　分裂した
She's top-notch! She split in two.
Okay,
さあ こっちも
仕事にかかろうかしら
now we're going to make our move as well!
見えた
Gotcha.
お… お前 何やった？
Wh-What's up with you?
メガネが壊れました
My glasses... broke down.
この空間がハッキングされている
This Space is being hacked!
Where's the hacking coming from?
一体 どこからハッキングしてる？
Access to the domain she's in is blocked!
あいつのいるドメインからの
アクセスは全て はじいてるぞ
The attack is coming from two different places!
攻撃は２か所からです
Why that...!
おのれ！　１つはフミエに違いない
No doubt one of them is Fumie...
So they're working together.
ヤツら結託したんだ
I don't think so. Look over here!
（アキラ）
違います 見てください！
They're in a completely different area.
（ガチャギリ）
全然違う場所にいるな
So which is the real one?
（ダイチ）
じゃあ どっちが本物だ？
None of them is the real one.
どっちも本物じゃない 本物は…
The real one is...
Here!
いたわ！
んなバカな！
あいつら分裂したのか？
How could she possibly...!
Did she split in two or what?
Can you figure out where her real location is?
現実の場所は
どっちか分かるか？
She's using a proxy to disguise herself.
偽装している
I can try,
やってみるが
ヤツがボロでも出さないかぎり
but if she doesn't reveal herself, I'm not sure I can find her.
見つかるかどうか…
Namecchi.
ナメッチ！
Two years'
お年玉 ２年分…
otoshidama...
Namekawa!
滑川(なめかわ)！
（ナメッチ）へい！
Yeah!
You don't have glasses anymore, so work out with your legs!
お前 メガネないんだから足で稼げ
Go and take her glasses!
ヤツのメガネを取り上げてこい！
R-Right!
へ… へい
So they modified
（イサコ）空間の設計ミスを
あいつが改良したのか
a structural error of the Space...
I see.
なるほど
使い方を覚えると面白いわね
Learning how it works can be very useful.
Okay, boys.
よし お前たち いけ！
Go!
（モジョたち）モジョ！
Geez...
（フミエ）何よ
あいつ まだ見つけられないの？
Haven't they located her yet?
Hell,
まったく… 世話が焼けるわね
they're useless!
あれ？　場所が分かったぞ
１階の元理科室だ
I found her location!
She's inside the old lab on the first floor.
What?
なんだって？　なんで分かった？
And how did you find out?
Hmm... How did I get that?
なんで分かったんだろう…
Is there a shortcut linking there?
ショートカットはつながってるか？
Yes, there is.
あります
Alright!
ようし！　とっておきを出せ
Let's play our trump card!
Yeah!
へい
Huh? It's not here!
あれ？　な… ないよ
What?!
（ダイチ）何？
クソ！　ナメッチに電話して…
Dammit!
Call Namecchi—
Ah, he hasn't got glasses!
あっ メガネないんだ あいつ…
直接 行くぞ！
Let's go there directly!
どてかましたれやー！
（ガチャギリ）おりゃー！
We'll blast her for good!
Yeah!
ああっ！　ま… 待って！
W-Wait!
（ナメッチ）イ… イサコちゃん？
Isako...
いますか～？
Are you in here?
For the teacher's personal use inside the lab.
ヘヘッ 使えるかな
I wonder if I can use 'em...
Recovering from Standby
Starting OS
イヤ～！
なんてことなの… これも偽物？
What's going on?
Another fake?
本体が出しているコマンドを
逆探知すれば…
If only we could trace back to the real one
that's giving the commands.
あと もうちょっと…
Just a little more...
見つけたわ！
Found her!
チェッ 入れない
I can't get in.
This is...
これは… 障壁だわ
A firewall!
Number Five, don't eat it,
（イサコ）５番 食うな　死ぬぞ
or you'll die.
（モジョ）ジョ…
よーし 発射準備！
Alright.
Prepare to move out!
Another hacker?
別の客か
Just wait.
待ってなさい
今 片づけるから
I'll take care of you, too.
If only I could find an unguarded spot...
（フミエ）隙さえ見つかれば…
Here it is!
隙ができた！
It went through!
通った！
I hope she doesn't notice it.
気づくなよ
The only weapons we have left are these firecrackers.
残りの武器は
このカンシャクだけだ
Don't fail!
落とすなよ
Charge!
（ダイチ）突っ込めー！
（ガチャギリ）やあー！
This toy is very interesting.
（イサコ）このオモチャ面白いな
もらっておくわ
I'll just keep it for myself.
You're finally here.
お待たせ
I'll let you play with me.
遊んであげる
D-Damn it!
こ… この！
Well done.
やるね
With all my power...!
じ… 実力で
Fumie...
フミエちゃん？
I told you I would use all of my power to make you understand!
じ… 実力で
分からせてやるんだから！
This old method
古流じゃ 所詮(しょせん) ムリムリ
is useless!
Smash it!
潰れろ！
Connection Interrupted
Fumie?
フ… フミエちゃん？
This means that Daichi
ショートカットを使えるのは
ダイチだけじゃないってことよ
Download is Complete
isn't the only one able to use shortcuts.
So she was even able to steal some information from me.
私から情報をかすめ取るとはね
I understand your real power,
実力は分かったわ 小さな魔女さん
little witch.
Four years'
（ナメッチ）お年玉 ４年分…
otoshidama...
Ah, my back is so stiff!
（フミエ）
あ～ 肩こった！　寿命 縮んだ
I've lost years of my life...
You were great, Fumie.
すごかったわ フミエちゃん
Well?
どうどう？　情報 見えた？
Can you see anything useful?
This is no good.
（メガばあ）こりゃダメじゃな
乱暴に引き抜いたんで壊れとる
You grabbed it in the middle of a fight, so it got corrupted.
え～　じゃあ
私の苦労はムダだったの？
So all my efforts were useless?
But we can read something in this piece.
まあ でも この辺だけは
なんとか読めるな
Just that?!
これだけ？
あ～ ムダに年取った
I lost years in vain.
Preview
Next time on Dennou Coil:
Metabug Scramble Bus Tour.
Metabug Scramble
Bus Tour
See you next time!
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
〝メタバグ争奪
バスツアー 〞
お楽しみに